Contact

+2347030409245 (Work) chisomthaddeusonu@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/chisomonu-7a0b3b80 (LinkedIn) chisomonu.com/ (Personal)

Top Skills

.NET

HTML

Project Management

Certifications

Certified Project Manager (CPM)
C# Test Driven Development
Fluent API Development in C#

Chisom Onu

Senior Software Developer (Backend) at FirstBank Nigeria

Summary

I am a senior software engineer with lots of hands-on development experiences and solved challenges in Microsoft .Net Development environment.

I live out development not just as a job but also as a lifestyle which has made me to be on the look out for collaborative learning environments and work teams. I am always open to fresh ideas and new technology stack once you can prove how effective the technology is in solving problems. I love to work hard with good sense of smartness and equally love to be appreciated for these.

I am a team player and do well in supervisory role too especially with young developers who needs grooming. I am a fan of clean coding as a software engineering principle.

This, thus, summarizes Chisom Onu

Experience

FirstBank Nigeria
Senior Software Developer (Backend)
November 2018 - Present

Lagos, Nigeria

- # Review approved Function Requirement Document (FRD) document from project stakeholders.
- # Design and develop application architecture based on approved FRD.
- # Translate approved FRD and architecture into application features for development.
- # Develop application for user review, User Acceptance Test (UAT) and Quality Assurance (QA).
- # Enhance and provide 3rd-level support to already existing software applications.

GTBank

Technology Officer

March 2018 - October 2018 (8 months)

Lagos, Nigeria

- # Review approved Business Requirement Document(BRD) document from project stakeholder.
- # Design and develop application architecture based on approved BRD.
- # Translate approved BRD and architecture into application features for development.
- # Develop application for User Acceptance Test (UAT) and Quality Assurance (QA).
- # Enhance and support already existing software applications.

EMIFast I.T Solution Limited

Microsoft .Net Developer (Contract)

August 2017 - February 2018 (7 months)

Access Bank Plc, Plot 161E, Idejo Street, Victoria Island, Lagos

- # Review approved Business Requirement Specification (BRS) document from stakeholder.
- # Design and develop application architecture based on approved BRS.
- # Translate approved BRS and architecture into application features for development.
- # Develop application for UAT and quality assurance tests.
- # Enhance and support already existing software applications.

Ranna Consultancy LTD Senior Software Developer

October 2016 - July 2017 (10 months)

Enugu

- # Designed and Developed a School Management Solution (idealSchool) for Tertiary Institutions.
- # Designed and Developed an Enterprise School Solution for Secondary Schools viz SmarterKiddies.
- # Developed a CommentBot a bot for driving traffic with auto interactivity on Facebook.
- # Developed a Sale of Online Forms portal with Remita Payment Integration.

Tenece Professional Services

Software Developer

April 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 7 months)

Enugu, Nigeria

- # Enhanced and Supported an Enterprise School Management Solution (School Manager) at several universities in the eastern part of Nigeria.
- # Trained and Supervised Junior Developers to achieve desired tasks.
- # Business Intelligence reporting with SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS).
- # Web API development.
- # Payment set-up and integration on SchoolManager viz eTranzact, Remita, Interswitch.
- # Enhanced, Supported and Piloted TestPro a computer-based test software for most universities in South-East viz University of Nigeria.

National Youth Service Corps
Corp Member/ Freelance Developer
March 2013 - February 2014 (1 year)
Usugbenu Grammer School, Ididigba, Esan Central, Irrua, Edo State

Scientific Equipment Development Institute Software Development Trainee April 2011 - October 2011 (7 months) Okpara Mine Road, Akwuke, Enugu State

Education

University of Nigeria, Nsukka
Bachelor of Engineering (BEng), Electronic Engineering
(Software) · (2007 - 2012)

University of Nigeria Secondary School SSCE/NECO · (2000 - 2006)

Model Primary School, maryland First School Leaving Cert. · (1994 - 2000)